Guide to the Vassar College Class Monograms Collection
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Class Monograms Collection
1868-1924
Vassar College
0.4 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
This collection consists of stamped and printed monograms for Vassar College graduating classes, as well as for a few sororities and other organizations.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of stamped and printed monograms for Vassar College graduating classes, as well as for a few sororities and other organizations.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into groupings by type of monogram and sub-arranged chronologically.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Document Types:
Monograms
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Audiovisuals and Realia
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, 2024.
Acquisition Information
Many of the monograms in this collection appear to have been collected by Vassar College librarians Frances A. Wood and Adelaide Underhill between 1905 and 1917.
Container List
- Class Monograms [Mounted]
  - 1868-1869 (Box 1)
  - 1870, [2 versions] (Box 1)
  - 1871 (Box 1)
  - 1872, [2 versions] (Box 1)
  - 1874 (Box 1)
  - 1876-1893 (Box 1)
  - 1894-1923 (Box 2)
- Class Monograms from Letters and Envelopes
  - 1872-1874 (Folder 3.1)
  - 1880-1889 (Folder 3.2)
  - 1890-1899 (Folder 3.3)
  - 1900-1909 (Folder 3.4)
  - 1910-1918 (Folder 3.5)
  - 1922, 1924 (Folder 3.6)
- Sorority and Miscellaneous Monograms
  - 1877-1880, undated (Folder 3.7)